# **Gabrielle Jacobs**

# Front End Web Developer

• Dallas, TX, 75287

469-626-7843

☑ GMJacobsDev@gmail.com

**★** GMJacobsDev.com

**in** Linkedin.com/in/gabrielle-jacobs

Github.com/GabbyJ



# **PROFILE**

Passionate front-end web developer with 4+ years of experience designing, developing, and managing responsive websites in the digital media industry with a multimedia background. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript; plus modern libraries and frameworks. Seeking an opportunity to contribute web development and multimedia skills in an environment that encourages learning and growth.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**React Developer** 10/2020 – 12/2020

The Collab Lab

Remote

- Working on a team of early-career developers under the guidance of experienced professionals
- Using Agile processes to build a production progressive web app (PWA) using React and Firebase over the course of 8 weeks
- Emphasizes pair programming, peer reviewing, and participating in weekly demos and retros.

#### **Digital Content and Wordpress Lead**

Wieck ☑

- Fix bugs and add website features to production 80% quicker than average by streamlining the ticketing process
- Improve the design and function of custom pages by adding CSS/ JS customizations
- Achieve a 1-on-1 line of communication for all 6 Wordpress clients to provide assistance, updates, and maintenance 50% faster
- Create custom templates from stage to production 60% quicker by both streamlining the ticketing process and providing unique customization knowledge
- Continue Content Management Specialist duties

## **Digital Content Management Specialist**

Wieck ☑

- 1 of 4 employees responsible for updating 15+ websites with releases, social media, images, videos, and graphics
- Provide internal and external support with an average 30 min turn around for multiple major car, health, and news corporations, an airline, and others
- Inform thousands of people on important corporate news within 30 mins through custom email blasts for 10+ countries/divisions

11/2019 – present Richardson, TX

06/2017 – 11/2019 Richardson, TX

#### **Customer Service**

Amusement Park/Retail

05/2015 – 11/2016 Pittsburgh, PA/Dallas, TX

**Media Intern**Shoutside Media
Pittsburgh, PA

- Built and maintained 3 Wordpress sites for lawyers and doctors
- Responsible for recording professional quality commercials and stock footage for 5 local companies
- Improved video editing techniques using Adobe Premiere and After Effects

#### **SKILLS**

**Languages** (HTML, CSS, Javascript (ES6), Python)

**Frameworks/Libraries** (SCSS (Sass), Bootstrap, jQuery, React, Node, Express)

**Dev Tools** (Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, NPM, Wordpress, Netlify)

**Design Tools** (Photoshop, Adobe XD, CodePen, Canva)

Miscellaneous (Responsive Design, Accessibility, Jira, Google Analytics, Agile, Microsoft Office)

**Soft Skills** (Problem Solving, Creativity, Willingness to learn, Self Starter, Dependable, Communication, Teamwork)

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Graphic Communications & Multimedia

California University of Pennsylvania

• 3.3 GPA

08/2012 – 12/2015 California, PA

## **CERTIFICATES**

### **Responsive Web Design**

FreeCodeCamp - Proven knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, Responsiveness, and Accessibility - Completed: 2019

#### **MERN Full Stack Web Development**

Udemy – Focuses on React, Node, Express, MongoDB. Also covers Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, EJS, SQL, Authentication – In Progress...

### **COMMUNITY CONTRIBUTIONS**

Hacktoberfest 10/2020

Open Source Contributor

FreeCodeCamp Dallas 09/2018 - 03/2020

Mentor, Participant Dallas, TX

 Work with Dallas students to complete the responsive Web Design Certificate on FreeCodeCamp and assist them with code-alongs at meet ups